That's good, give me more.
好喝，我還要
Hey, drink up.
喝掉
That's not it!
不是這個！
Hey, come here!
過來！
Want to try it? Drink it.
想嚐看看嗎？喝吧
You can drink it.
妳可以喝
Cheers.
乾杯
Why? Hey, you.
怎麼了？喂
What is it? What's wrong?
幹嘛啊？怎麼回事？
Do you hate me?
討厭我嗎？
Just do it!
乖乖照做！
What's this?
怎麼回事啊？
You'd like to buy her for the night?
你是要買她過夜嗎？
So, you're the Madame?
妳就是閣長？
Talking to her is like talking to a wall.
和她講話就像對牛彈琴
You speak Korean very well.
你的韓語講得非常好
That's because I've spent many nights with Joseon bitches.
那是因為我很多次 和朝鮮婊子共度春宵啊
And tonight, it'll be her.
今晚輪到她了
They're not prostitutes.
她們不是妓女
They are artists.
是藝人
If I say I'll be paying,
只要我說我要買
you'd better sell art and your bodies too.
妳們最好乖乖地賣藝也賣身
And if we don't?
假如我們不答應呢？
Then, there will be a hole in her head.
那我會在她頭上開個洞
How about me?
換我怎麼樣？
If you'll have me, instead of that girl.
由我代替那個女生
Wow. Amazing!
太好了！
How much are you worth?
妳值多少錢？
Even better. I'm free.
更便宜，免費的
You're a cheap one, huh?
原來妳是便宜貨啊？
Strip her.
脫光她的衣服
Yes, sir.
是
On one condition.
我有一個條件
A condition?
條件？
If you defeat me in a drinking contest,
如果你能夠在喝酒比試中贏過我
do whatever you'd like with me.
我便任你處置
You're an interesting bitch. If I win, I'll have you…
這個賤人好有趣 如果我贏了，我不僅要妳…
and I'll take this wrist too.
還要這一隻手腕
-If it pleases you, sir. -On one condition.
-悉聽尊便 -但我有一個條件
I will set the rules.
規則由我定
Goodness, eat slowly.
天哪，吃慢點
EPISODE 3
（第 3 集）
You have quite the colorful life, huh?
你活得也太精彩了吧？
You only just got here, but you already got drafted, hired,
剛來不久就當過兵、被錄用過
and even robbed?
甚至還被打劫過？
Please buy me a gun.
請大人幫我買一把槍
What for? You've always been afraid of guns, no?
要槍做什麼？ 你不是一直很怕槍的嗎？
I'm going to fight for independence.
我要參加獨立運動
We are here…
我們來這裡…
on a mission to protect the era we're from.
是為了執行任務 保護我們所屬的時代
Catch the red-white mask,
抓到紅白面具人
find the Guardian Stone, and return safely.
找到守護石並安全地返回去
-That's our mission. -But still--
-這才是我們的任務 -可是…
If you insist on fighting, don't think about returning home.
如果你堅持參加獨立運動 那就不要回家了
Stay here and take responsibility.
留下來盡你的義務吧
Humans in this era are risking their bloody lives fighting.
這個時代的人類正在冒死戰鬥
Are you sure we can go back?
你確定我們回得去嗎？
We must.
我們一定要回去啊
They don't even have Wi-Fi here.
這裡連無線網路都沒有
No mint chocolate either.
也沒有薄荷巧克力味的冰淇淋
Nor my Ji-ah.
也沒有我的智雅
But you have Lord Lee Rang here.
但是這裡有李朗大人啊
Hey, I saw him almost die as soon as I got here.
拜託，我剛到這裡就看到他差點死掉
I thought my heart would explode.
我的心臟都要爆炸了
But you saved him.
但是你救了他啊
I hope he does well without me.
希望他一個人可以好好生活
But he's playing boss of some bandit gang.
可是他跑去當土匪頭目
I don't know if I could leave him behind.
真不知道我能不能拋下他
When are you going to tell him?
你打算什麼時候告訴他？
Tell him what?
告訴他什麼？
That I'll disappear after a month?
我會在一個月後消失嗎？
You have to give him time to accept that you're not here to stay.
你總要給他一些時間 接受你不能久留的事實啊
Oh, dear.
天哪
-Eat up. -What if she loses?
-吃吧 -如果她輸掉怎麼辦？
-Gosh, what should we do? -Oh, no. This is bad.
-天哪，我們怎麼辦？ -不行啊，這下糟糕了
Rang.
阿朗
Goodness, what do we do?
天哪，怎麼辦？
Shouldn't we stop her?
要不要阻止閣長？
Let's begin!
開始吧！
Oh, no.
不會吧
She might die doing this!
這樣可能會喝死的！
What do we do?
怎麼辦？
Incompetent fools.
無能的笨蛋
I'm okay. I can still drink.
我沒事，我還可以喝
Get me a jar.
給我拿一罐酒來
Hey! Bring us a jar!
給我們拿一罐酒來！
Oh, my! Oh, wow!
天哪！
Yeah. That's more like it, Ryu Hong-joo.
這樣才對嘛，柳紅朱
But where did this punk go? Rang? Rang!
那個臭小子去哪了？阿朗！
Your men are so weak.
你手下的男人太弱了
Can they even do a man's deed properly?
他們真的能做好男人該做的事嗎？
You wretched geisha!
妳這該死的藝妓！
It's broken.
壞掉了
Will you give it to me?
可以送給我嗎？
Gosh.
天哪
You bitch, next time I'll definitely--
賤人，下次我一定…
Who are you?
妳是誰？
You like the gayageum, no?
你喜歡伽倻琴是吧？
You're alive. You're alive in this era.
你還活著，你還活在這個時代
I will never give up on you.
我永遠不會放棄你的
Plus, the answer to your question can also be found in here.
而且你想要的答案也在裡面
He is Lee Yeon…
他是李硯…
And yet, he's not.
又不是李硯
Then what is he?
那他是什麼？
A mermaid?
人魚？
I'll show you how to tie it.
我教你如何繫領帶
What's this? A circus?
這是什麼？馬戲團嗎？
What's with the tail?
那條尾巴是怎麼回事？
Shut up!
閉嘴！
Hear, hear!
沒錯！
Do it!
上吧！
Shall we see if that's a real tail?
要不要看看這條尾巴是真是假？
-What the hell! -Be quiet, will you?
-什麼鬼啊！ -閉嘴好嗎？
Damn it!
該死！
-You're a real mermaid, aren't you? -A half-blood. Father's a human fisherman.
-妳是真正的人魚吧？ -半人半魚，我父親是人類漁夫
-And you're here because? -I want to become a singer.
-妳為什麼來這裡？ -我想當歌手
Whether you become a singer or a spectacle,
要麼當歌手，要麼當一隻珍奇異獸
just do one or the other.
妳只能選擇其一
Hold on!
等一下！
This is my scale.
這是我的鱗片
-If you ever need me-- -I don't need it.
-如果哪天需要我… -不需要
Take it.
收下吧
I said no need.
我講過了，不需要
Goodbye.
再見
The tie suits you well.
這條領帶很適合你
Why did you do all that, for someone like me?
閣長何苦要為我這樣的人 做到這種程度？
Because I only distinguish the world into two categories.
因為在我看來 這世界上的人只分為兩類
Those on my side, and those who are not.
我的人和非我的人
I'll either risk my life to protect, or risk my life to destroy.
我會拼命保護前者 也會拼命毀滅後者
You're the first person.
閣長是第一個
The first person to treat gisaengs like human beings.
第一個把妓生視為人的人
Did you cry earlier?
妳之前哭過了？
No, I didn't cry until the end.
沒有，直到最後才哭的
Just as you taught me not to, Madame.
我有按照閣長教我的規矩做
Good job.
很好
-Are you full? -Not even.
-閣長飽了嗎？ -才沒有
I drank so much without a snack, my stomach feels empty.
沒有下酒菜，喝掉那麼多酒 胃裡感覺空空的
Shall I grill some neobiani for you?
要我做烤牛肉片給閣長吃嗎？
Where can he be at this hour?
這麼晚了，他會去哪裡呢？
Gosh, that brat.
真是的，那個臭小子
Aren't you sleeping?
還不睡嗎？
-What've you been up to? -I was drinking. Why?
-去哪裡了？ -出去喝酒了，怎樣？
Your new curfew is 10 p.m.
你的宵禁時間改成晚上十點
Crazy fool.
瘋子
I don't trust you.
我才不信你呢
Who is there?
是誰？
You must be the gatekeeper.
你一定是守門人沒錯了
You reek of blood.
你渾身散發著血腥味
As a descendant of the Siberian tiger,
作為東北虎的後代
how can you covet such impious things?
你竟敢覬覦這些邪惡的東西？
Because I am impious.
因為我同樣邪惡
Go back.
回去吧
All that's left in that jar
那個罐子裡
is resentment and regret.
只剩下憎恨和遺憾了
That's also what's left inside of me.
那也正是我心裡僅剩的東西
The seal hasn't been broken in over 500 years.
已經封印了五百多年，未曾被打開過
But today…
但是今天…
it will be broken.
我要打開它
Take this!
接招！
That's enough, sir.
夠了
My stove's boiling nurungji, so I better go before it burns.
我的爐子上正在煮鍋巴 我要在它糊掉之前趕回去
Strike him!
動手！
It's a fire.
火
You poor little thing.
可憐人啊
Go.
去吧
Show Lee Yeon your pretty eyes.
給李硯看看妳這雙漂亮的眼睛
What do you want?
妳想要什麼？
This?
這個嗎？
It must be special to you.
它對妳而言一定很特別
Where are you?
你在哪裡？
Found you.
找到了
Look at me.
看著我
Why did you do it? Why did you break your promise? Why?
你為什麼那樣做？ 為什麼違背諾言？為什麼？
-What? What's going on? -Someone is in our room.
-什麼？怎麼了？ -我們房間裡有人
I don't see anyone. Did you have a dream?
我沒看到什麼人啊，是不是做夢了？
I'm sure someone was here.
我很確定有人來過
What? Who was here?
什麼？誰來過？
I don't know.
我不知道
I don't know what it is, but…
不知道那是什麼，但…
I feel like I saw something I shouldn't have.
我好像看到了不該看的東西
Gosh.
天哪
Look who it is.
看看這是誰
What are you doing here, Master?
主人，妳怎麼來了？
Because I own this place.
因為這是我的地盤
Oh, no wonder. I-- I couldn't sleep well last night.
難怪，我昨晚一直睡不安穩
How dare you run from me to go serve Lee Yeon?
你竟敢從我身邊逃走 跑去侍奉李硯？
-You tried to kill me! -I told you to stay out of my sight, no?
-因為妳想殺我嘛！ -我不是說過別出現在我面前！
Come here! Koo Shin-ju!
過來！具申炷！
No. Everything that comes into my forest is mine.
不行，進入我林子的東西都是我的
Koo Shin-ju.
具申炷
Mark my words.
記住我的話
Next time I see you,
下次我見到你時
consider your arms and legs gone.
一定會卸掉你的四肢
Please have mercy!
饒命啊！
Let's start with a beating.
先打一頓再說吧
No! No!
不要啊！
Shin-ju, you there?
申炷，你在嗎？
Lord Lee Yeon!
李硯大人！
-Hey. -So great to see you again, Shin-ju!
-嘿 -很高興又見面了，申炷！
Gosh, you've gotten even cuter.
天哪，你變得更帥了
You two know each other?
你們認識嗎？
Oh, that's right!
對喔！
Eat some more.
再吃一點
I don't want to. I'm full.
不要，我飽了
Gosh, you look so thin and weak.
天哪，看你瘦弱的樣子
-Eat. You should gain some weight. -Who are you to tell me what to do?
-吃吧，你應該長胖一點 -你有什麼資格命令我？
-Stop acting up or else… -Then what? What will you do?
-不要胡鬧了，不然… -不然什麼？你要怎樣？
In goes the airplane!
飛機！
Damn, you're childish!
該死，幼稚！
Then eat up already.
那就快點吃吧
Baby, I'll be back soon.
寶貝，我很快就回來
-Geez, she's deeply sick. -Hey, what about the red-white mask?
-天哪，她病得不輕 -那個紅白面具人怎麼辦？
-You idiot. -You find the bastard?
-傻瓜 -妳找到那個混蛋了？
I'm not sure.
不一定
-I'll tell you if you treat me well. -Geez. Hey!
-你對我好一點，我就告訴你 -真是的，拜託喔！
But I'm a little busy right now.
但我現在有點忙
-So did she find him or not? -Who knows what she's thinking.
-她到底有沒有找到他啊？ -誰知道她在想什麼
I'm curious.
我很好奇
What exactly is your relationship with that crazy woman?
你和那個瘋女人究竟是什麼關係？
Let's swear to protect each other no matter what.
我們來發誓無論如何都要保護彼此
Let's become mountain gods and reunite again.
以後當了山神再相聚
Hey, Cheon Moo-yeong!
千無影！
Promise!
保證！
Promise.
保證
Well, what is it?
怎麼了？
It's something like a broken oath.
和違背諾言有關係
Eat, eat.
吃吧
There's someone here to see you.
這裡有個人想見你
Who?
誰？
Ta-da.
看
What's with the flowers?
為什麼送花給我？
Well,
因為
because those are your favorite flowers.
這是妳最喜歡的花
You remember that too?
你還記得？
You are the Cheon Moo-yeong I know.
果然還是我熟悉的那個千無影
I have a ton of questions.
我有一大堆問題想問你
Rumor says that Taluipa removed you from your post
傳言說奪衣婆撤掉了你的職務
and turned you into stone.
還把你變成了石柱
-It's true. -But the old hag liked you the most.
-沒錯 -但是老妖婆最喜歡的就是你
So, why?
她為什麼那樣做？
-I did something deserving it. -You were punished for hundreds of years?
-是我活該 -你被罰了幾百年？
I turned into stone and was imprisoned!
我被變成石柱，還被監禁了！
I survived, thinking of you.
但我心裡想著妳而熬過來了
Our beautiful Hong-joo.
我們的美人紅朱
I hoped that you'd be living happily, with your seven younger brother owls.
我只盼著 妳和七隻貓頭鷹弟弟幸福地活下去
Perhaps you don't know.
看來你還不知道
My parents and siblings…
我的父母和弟弟…
all starved to death.
全部餓死了
When I got home, they were corpses.
我回到家中時，他們已經變成屍體了
After all that pestering that I become a mountain god to support them…
他們曾經總是纏著我 要我當山神養活他們…
Those incompetent and weak, yet nice, can't even protect their own.
軟弱無能又待人客氣的人 連自己人都保護不了
I'm sorry.
對不起
I wasn't there for you as a friend.
我這個朋友沒有陪在妳身邊
Nothing to be sorry about.
沒有必要道歉
Let me just ask one thing.
我問你一件事
You and Lee Yeon. What happened between you two?
你和李硯之間發生什麼事了？
How did you, who couldn't even kill an ant,
你這個曾連螞蟻都不捨得殺害的人
think to stab Yeon's brother?
怎麼會刺傷他弟弟？
Because I want Yeon to feel the same pain I felt.
因為我想讓阿硯體會一下我的痛苦
Like when I lost my only brother.
我失去唯一的哥哥時那種痛苦
What's this about?
怎麼回事？
Yeon is on his way.
阿硯要來找我了
Your identity is a secret, no?
你的身份不是保密的嗎？
I want to check something.
我想確認一件事
It was you who wanted to see me?
想見我的人是妳嗎？
You left like that earlier,
之前還趾高氣昂地離開
but what's with the flowers, huh?
現在又要送花給我？
What's going on?
怎麼回事？
It suddenly became dark.
突然天黑了
What are you doing?
你在做什麼？
I can't…
我不能…
Hong-joo. Where are you, Hong-joo?
紅朱，妳在哪裡？
What's wrong with him?
他怎麼了？
Yeon.
阿硯
Yeon, what's wrong? You okay?
阿硯，怎麼了？你還好嗎？
Hong-joo. Why am I like this?
紅朱，我怎麼會變成這樣？
What's happening to me?
我怎麼了？
What's going on?
怎麼了？
Did something happen?
發生什麼事了嗎？
Someone's here.
有人來了
Who?
誰？
The flower merchant.
花商
Hong-joo.
紅朱
What's happening to me, huh?
我怎麼了？
Let's go. I'll take you home.
走吧，我送你回家
You still…
妳對李硯…
have feelings for Lee Yeon.
依然舊情未了
Like back then.
當初是這樣
And until now.
現在還是這樣
Perhaps I should have checked.
我早該確認清楚的
My eyes… What's wrong with my eyes?
我的眼睛…我的眼睛怎麼了？
Lord Lee Yeon, take a deep breath.
李硯大人，深吸一口氣
Open your eyes.
睜開眼睛
Do you see anything?
有看到什麼嗎？
No, I don't.
沒有
The lighter, please.
打火機給我一下
I'll check your pupil reflex.
我幫你檢查瞳孔反射
Well…
那個…
There's no response.
沒反應
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
Tell me!
告訴我！
I think you've lost your sight.
看來你失明了
Look at me, look at me.
看著我
That girl from last night.
昨晚那個女孩子
What?
什麼？
It's that thing.
是那個東西
It all started after I met its eyes.
一切都是從我與她對視後開始的
What's that bell?
那個鈴鐺是什麼？
Someone gave it, saying I did something nice.
別人送我的，說我做了好事
You used to be human?
妳曾經是人類嗎？
My name.
我的名字
Guess my name.
猜猜我的名字
Name?
名字？
What does that matter? When you're so special right now.
名字重要嗎？畢竟妳現在很特別
No! The nine-tailed fox knows!
不行！那隻九尾狐知道！
-What? -What are you trying to do?
-什麼？ -你是想怎樣？
Don't look! You can't make eye contact.
不要看！不要有眼神接觸
Who is that kid?
那個小孩是誰？
I am Saetani.
我是塞陀尼
Saetani?
塞陀尼？
A monster created by a Yeommae ritual.
用女巫術創造的怪物
Go inside.
妳先進去
YEOMMAE - STARVING A CHILD TO PRACTICE DIVINATION
（女巫術 要小孩挨餓來占卜的巫術）
Have you lost your mind?
你瘋了嗎？
You released a cursed monster into this world.
居然將一個被詛咒的怪物放到世間
How is Yeon doing? Is he distressed?
阿硯怎麼樣？痛苦嗎？
Is he writhing in the dark?
有沒有在黑暗中苦惱地扭動身體？
Is this what you wanted?
這是你想要的結果嗎？
Lee Yeon must be punished for breaking the oath.
李硯必須因為違背諾言而受罰
The oath?
諾言？
We swore to protect each other even if we died.
我們曾發誓至死保護彼此
But one guy falls for a human and abandons his duties.
但是其中一個人愛上人類 拋棄了職責
The other commits a heinous crime to have been turned into stone
另一個人犯下滔天罪行 被曾經待他如親生兒子的奪衣婆
at Taluipa's hands who was like a mother to him.
變成了石柱
There was no one by my side.
只剩下我一個人
Even when I needed you guys.
即便是在我最需要你們的時候
-Hong-joo-- -Finally.
-紅朱… -終於
The three of us have finally reunited.
我們三個終於團聚了
But why is it like this?
為什麼要這樣？
Come to me.
來我身邊吧
Whatever you want,
無論妳要什麼
I'll give it to you.
我都會給妳的
Just in case, try to minimize eye irritation.
盡量減少對眼部的刺激，以防萬一
I wonder what that girl was?
那個女孩是什麼東西？
I don't know about that, but it's a powerful kind of curse.
不知道，但這是一種很厲害的詛咒
Just looking at it puts a curse on you? I've never heard of a demon like that.
看一眼就被詛咒了？ 我從來沒有聽說過這樣的妖怪
That's not the problem.
這不是重點
Who would think to deliver a curse to me
想想看，誰會在1938年
in the year 1938, to the exact address of Myoyeongak?
派人來妙緣閣詛咒我？
Red-white mask.
紅白面具人
Shin-ju, fix my eyes.
申炷，治好我的眼睛
I don't have time for this.
我沒有時間耗下去了
I'll try to find a way.
我會盡力想辦法的
Give him porridge. He'll need the energy.
餵他喝粥，他必須補充體力
You still hate me, huh?
你還在恨我嗎？
I kept you with me for selfish reasons,
我自私地把你留在身邊
but you're confused as to why,
你卻不知道原因
and whether you can even trust me.
甚至不確定能不能相信我
You think my eyes haven't been watching you these past few days?
你以為過去幾天裡 我沒有觀察你嗎？
You're not the Lee Yeon I know.
你不是我認識的李硯
That's the only reason I kept you alive.
這是我留你一條命的唯一原因
No.
不對
You needed family.
真正的原因是你需要家人
Whether I'm real or fake.
無論我是真是假
Shut up. I could kill you right here, if I wanted to.
閉嘴，只要我願意 現在就可以殺了你
I've met many monsters throughout my life.
我從小到大見過很多妖怪
Many times have I barely survived death, but not once was I ever afraid.
很多次死裡逃生，但我從來沒怕過
I'm a little afraid now.
我現在有點害怕
-You're afraid? -I can't protect anyone like this.
-你怕了？ -我現在這樣保護不了任何人
-Even if something happens to you. -Quit the older brother act.
-即便你遇到危險也無能為力 -不要再裝大哥了
No matter what others say, I'm your older brother.
不管別人怎麼講，我始終是你的哥哥
-I fed, dressed, and raised you. -So what?
-曾幫你餵飯穿衣，還把你養大成人 -所以呢？
Want me to repay kindness?
要我報恩嗎？
-Give it. I'll eat it myself. -Fine. Here.
-給我，我自己吃 -好啊，在這裡
Geez, I can't watch this any longer. Just give it to me.
天哪，我看不下去了，給我吧
Say, "Ah."
說“啊”
Geez.
真是的
Again.
再來
Gosh, be a little nicer. I'm a patient.
天哪，客氣一點，我是病人耶
You happy?
滿意了吧？
Damn, it tastes bad.
該死，好難吃
-Next time, bring mung bean porridge. -Who do you think you are?
-下次我要綠豆粥 -你以為你是誰啊？
Where are you going in that state?
你這副樣子要去哪裡？
The red-white mask will come.
紅白面具人會來的
-Go on. -Think about it.
-繼續 -想想看
I can't see a thing. Would you miss this opportunity?
我失明了 換作是你，你會錯過這個機會嗎？
So, you'll do what without sight?
那你看不見又能做什麼呢？
I have to try something. I should at least walk on my own.
總要努力吧，至少應該學會自己走路
Wait, stop there.
等一下，站住
Five steps to the left.
往左五步
One, two, three, four, five.
一、二、三、四、五
There, now turn right.
好了，現在右轉
That's a flower bed, you idiot.
那是花圃啦，笨蛋
Oh, a flower bed.
花圃啊
Nine.
九
Ten.
十
Seventeen.
十七
Seventeen steps from the flower bed.
從花圃走過來有十七步
What's this?
這是什麼？
-It's gangjeong. Have one. -Gangjeong?
-糯米韓菓，吃一個 -糯米韓菓？
Shit-- What's this? It smells weird.
可惡，這是什麼？聞起來怪怪的
-It's dog poop. -Hey, you prick! Seriously!
-是狗屎啦 -混蛋！真是的！
Where are you?
你在哪裡？
Wait till you get caught. Okay?
敢被我抓到試試？
Hey, damn it! You little--
該死！臭小子…
What's so exciting?
有什麼好開心的？
-Where are you? -Over here, here!
-你在哪裡？ -這邊！
I, Sho Tawara,
我，俵祥羽
and my wife Seiko, a native noble.
以及我的妻子靖子，日本的貴族
Today, we have dedicated two airplanes to the Imperial Forces,
今天向皇軍捐獻了兩架飛機
and it burns our heart with patriotism.
這使我們心裡充滿了愛國主義情懷
The peace of the 24 million subjects is solely attributable
兩千四百萬百姓的安寧
to the brave Imperial Forces
全靠英勇的皇軍
and His Majesty, the emperor!
和天皇陛下的護佑！
What do you think?
怎麼樣？
It's for when he receives his Order of Military Merit.
這是他為軍功章頒獎典禮準備的致辭
It's nice, but at the end…
很不錯，但是最後…
"Long live the Emperor! Long live the Empire of Japan!"
“天皇萬歲！大日本帝國萬歲！”
How about adding this in?
加上這一句怎麼樣？
Perfect!
完美！
How wonderful!
太棒了！
Those who listen will naturally have their patriotic spirits soar.
聽眾的愛國之情自然會高漲的
-If it's two planes, how much is it? -Ten thousand won.
-兩架飛機要多少錢？ -一萬韓元
10,000 WON AT THE TIME
（當時的一萬韓元）
IS APPROXIMATELY FIVE BILLION WON NOW
（約等於現在的五十億韓元）
The Government-General is calling.
總督府來電
-Oh, please go ahead. Yes. -Yes.
-請吧 -好
Why don't you lighten up on a glorious day like this?
如此光榮的日子，為什麼不高興呢？
People might see you and think you're an independence activist.
大家看到妳這樣 可能會懷疑妳是獨立運動份子
I'm the only daughter of Sho Tawara, who's being awarded by the Emperor.
我是正在接受天皇授獎的 俵祥羽的獨生女
People might hear you and think you've gone mad.
大家聽到你的話，可能會以為你瘋了
When you're this sharp,
每次看到妳伶牙俐齒的樣子
I find it very charming.
我都會被妳迷住
Keep an eye on her.
盯著她
See what she's been up to with that pretty face.
看她頂著那張漂亮的臉蛋都在做什麼
You have a vague idea, no?
你是隱約知道的吧？
If I'm going to keep up the human act and devour Joseon,
如果我要繼續扮人類的模樣吞噬朝鮮
I need this family.
就需要這家人
And I wish for my adorable new bride to have not one speck of dirt on her.
而且我希望 我可愛的新娘身上沒有任何污點
-Lift your arms. -Geez.
-手臂抬起來 -天哪
-Here we go. -What's this?
-好了 -在幹嘛？
Damn it, you freak. Do you really want to die?
可惡，你這個變態，真的想死嗎？
-Let's have an exorcism. -What?
-我們舉行驅邪儀式吧 -什麼？
Exorcism? Will it work?
驅邪？會有用嗎？
Well, it's a traditional method but it'll get rid of most curses.
方法很傳統 但是可以驅走大部分詛咒
Give me your eye mask. I need something of yours.
把眼罩給我 我需要一件屬於你的東西
Sure.
好的
-We'll be back soon! -Be careful.
-我們很快就回來！ -小心一點
Oh, gosh.
天哪
Grapes?
葡萄？
When I think about my childhood, I still smell grapes.
一想到我的童年 我依然會聞到葡萄味
Geez, that damn temple.
天哪，那座該死的廟宇
It teemed with grapevines, hence it's name, Temple Vino.
那裡爬滿了葡萄藤，所以叫葡藤寺
For us, it's our hometown and orphanage.
對我們來講 那裡是故鄉，也是育幼院
What's so great about a mountain god?
山神有什麼了不起的？
We put our lives on the line for it.
我們居然願意冒死坐上那個位置
Sometimes I want to turn back time.
有時我希望時光可以倒流
So you don't have a human that you can't get over.
那樣的話 你沒有令你念念不忘的人類
Back to when you didn't have Shin-ju or your brother.
我們重新回到 沒有申炷和你弟弟的時候
When all we had were…
你和我…
each other to rely on.
只有彼此可以依靠
But we are no longer those children from that time.
但我們已經不是當初的小孩子了
I hope your sight never returns.
我希望你永遠不要復明
Why the sudden curse?
幹嘛突然詛咒我？
Being the only one living in the past irks me.
只有我還活在過去，這讓我很惱火耶
I'm dying to see you helpless without me.
我好想看看你沒了我會有多無助
You know that's not my thing.
妳知道的，“無助”這個詞不適合我
Yeon.
阿硯
I'm giving you a chance right now.
我正在給你機會
A chance?
機會？
When you close your eyes, you can see more than you think.
閉上眼睛時 可以看到的東西超乎你的想像
You must figure it out yourself.
你必須自己想明白
What to look for.
應該找什麼
What you missed with your eyes open.
你睜開眼睛的時候遺漏了什麼
You saw him.
妳看到他了
You saw what was behind that red-white mask, didn't you?
妳看過紅白面具人的真面目 對不對？
-You saw him too. -What?
-你也看到過 -什麼？
Say the word,
講出那個詞
and I might side with you.
我就可能和你聯手
Or else…
不然的話…
I could be a worse enemy than him.
我可能是比他更可怕的敵人
-Damn it. Let go of me. -Answer me. Say you're mine.
-該死，放開我 -回答我，說你是我的
-Why are you doing this? -Because I like you.
-妳為什麼這樣做？ -因為我喜歡你
Wrong.
錯
You just always have to get what you want.
妳只是總要得到妳想要的東西罷了
You just can't stand it if you don't.
得不到就不甘心
So, what's your answer?
所以你的答覆是什麼？
A fox never betrays his mate.
狐狸永遠不能背叛配偶
That's my answer.
這就是我的答覆
Jae-yoo.
載宇
Go spread some rumors to the demons of Gyeongseong.
散佈消息給京城的妖怪們
What sort of rumors?
什麼消息？
That Lee Yeon went blind.
李硯失明了
CLOSED TODAY
（今日歇業）
It's been so long since we last closed.
我們好久沒有歇業了
I might go to the bathhouse and soak in the hot tub.
我可能會去澡堂裡泡熱水澡
Really?
真的嗎？
But will it be all right?
但是這樣可以嗎？
Do we really leave the guest alone?
真的可以丟下客人不管嗎？
It's the Madame's orders. And for us, that's the law.
這是閣長的命令 對我們而言就是律法
Damn it.
該死
Is-- Is there anyone out there?
外面有人嗎？
Can I get some water?
可以給我一些水嗎？
Yes, sir. Did you need something?
先生，需要什麼東西嗎？
Who are you? I've never heard your voice.
你是誰？我從來沒有聽過你的聲音
They call me Sudol who carries firewood.
他們叫我壽石，我負責搬運木柴
-The gisaengs all went to the bathhouse. -I see…
-妓生們都去澡堂了 -這樣啊…
-Are you alone? -Yes, sir.
-就你一個人嗎？ -是的
-Give me a hand.
-扶我一下 -好的
Are you going someplace?
你要去什麼地方嗎？
Your name's Sudol, right?
你是叫壽石吧？
And what do you do here?
你在這裡做什麼工作？
I'm the guy who carries the firewood.
我負責搬運木柴
Is that so?
是嗎？
How strange.
那就奇怪了
What do you mean, sir?
什麼意思？
Because you have the hands of a swordsman!
這明明是劍客的手！
I'm guessing there are about 15 guys. Who the hell are you all?
我猜大約有十五個人，你們都是誰？
You know how many demons you've killed since working for Taluipa?
你知道自從為奪衣婆效力以來 你殺死過多少妖怪嗎？
You think I'll keep track in my diary?
你以為我會在日記裡逐一記錄嗎？
So much talk for a guy who can't even use his eyes.
一個看不見的瞎子竟敢如此囂張
You think foxes only hunt with their eyes?
你以為狐狸只靠眼睛狩獵嗎？
Exorcism or whatever-- Must we do it at a place like this?
驅不驅邪先不說 我們非要選在這樣的地方嗎？
It must be a path that humans frequent.
必須是人類常走的路才行
-What's with the red beans? -To chase away ghosts.
-撒紅豆做什麼？ -趕走鬼怪
You know they love rice cakes.
你知道的，他們喜歡吃年糕
Go away!
走開！
What time is it?
幾點了？
-Five to midnight. -It's almost time. Please, come in.
-距離午夜還有五分鐘 -時間快到了，進來吧
-Lord Lee Yeon's hair, please. -Here.
-請給我李硯大人的頭髮 -來
Please burn it at midnight.
請你在午夜時分燒掉它
Don't forget to pour alcohol north, east, west, and south.
不要忘記往東西南北四個方向倒酒
Okay. For the millionth time.
知道了，你講過一千遍啦
From here on, you're on your own.
從現在起，只能靠你自己了
Leave as soon as you're done.
完成儀式後馬上離開
Don't look back or talk until you arrive.
路上不要回頭，也不要講話
-Don't ever look back! -Just go.
-千萬不要回頭！ -快走吧
-Get him! -Why you--!
-殺了他！ -為什麼…
Jae-yoo.
載宇
Let's impair Yeon's hearing too.
我們來削弱阿硯的聽力吧
Yes, ma'am.
是
Shit…
該死…
How embarrassing. You running away?
好丟臉，你要逃跑嗎？
Take this!
看招！
Get him!
殺了他！
Wait, stop there. Five steps to the left.
等一下，站住，往左走五步
One, two, three, four…
一、二、三、四…
Five!
五！
It's here.
是這裡
Now, both parties are equally in the dark.
現在雙方都看不見了，很公平
Well, this is no fun.
真沒意思
Are you going out?
妳要出門嗎？
Taluipa summoned me. I killed a human yesterday.
奪衣婆召喚我，我昨天殺了一個人類
You sure you'll be okay, leaving Yeon behind by himself?
留下阿硯一個人，妳真的放心嗎？
Cook him up however you want.
隨便你如何處置他
Let's see what you've got.
拿出你的本事來
If you feel like something's chasing you, it's probably the creature.
如果你覺得有什麼東西在追你 可能是那個生物
Don't ever look back. Never.
千萬不要回頭，切記
It's a much more dangerous creature than I'd expected.
這個生物比我想的危險得多
I have a bad feeling.
我有一種不祥的預感
At this rate, it'll catch me.
照這樣下去，他會追上我的
Where are you headed, boss? Let's go together.
老大，要去哪裡啊？我們一起走吧
What's going on? Why are you pretending not to know me?
怎麼了？為什麼假裝不認識我啊？
No way--
不可能…
Are you embarrassed that I'm a rickshaw worker now?
該不會是因為 我是人力車夫而嫌棄我吧？
Gosh, why aren't you saying anything?
天哪，你為什麼不講話？
What?
什麼？
You mean, you have to go?
你是說你要走嗎？
Get on, then.
請上車
Ta-da!
看！
Why did you buy so much?
買這麼多做什麼？
You haven't smelled the ocean in so long, no? Have one.
妳很久沒有聞到海腥味了吧？ 吃一個吧
-Does it taste good? -Even better than crucian carp!
-好吃嗎？ -比鯽魚還好吃！
Wait, but what's all this?
等一下，這是什麼？
It's a gift.
送人的禮物
Remember the brothers from a few days ago?
記得幾天前那對兄弟嗎？
Oh, the older one? Lord Lee Yeon?
是要送給哥哥嗎？李硯大人？
No, the younger one.
不，是弟弟
Lee Rang?
李朗？
So his name is Rang.
原來他叫李朗啊
Don't do it, Yeo-hee. Don't get close to him.
不要啊，汝熙，不要靠近他
-Is he a bad guy? -A very…
-他是壞人嗎？ -非常…
He has a lot of wounds.
他有許多過往導致的心理創傷
He has one human parent, just like you.
他和妳一樣，也有一半人類血統
You know very well about those neither human nor demon,
妳很清楚那些非人非妖的生物
and the path they end up taking.
最終會走上哪條路
But it was love at first sight.
但我對他一見鐘情
I…
我…
I'm going to love that guy.
我要去愛他
Ma'am.
社長
There will be a bomb coming in from Shanghai soon.
有一顆炸彈很快要從上海運來了
I'll leave the back door open.
我會敞開後門的
Oh, what's the password?
暗號是什麼？
Do-re-mi-re-do.
Do Re Mi Re Do
-Be careful. -You too, ma'am.
-多加小心 -社長也要小心
Was the exorcism a success?
驅邪儀式成功了嗎？
At last,
終於
Yeon is all alone.
阿硯也無依無靠了
Hey, what's this?
這是什麼？
Wow!
哇！
Isn't this the castella from Jingogae that sells out like hot cakes?
這不是金鍋蓋熱銷的長崎蛋糕嗎？
Whoa, amazing!
太好吃了吧！
The bread is as fluffy as cotton candy!
口感像棉花糖一樣鬆軟！
Hey, Hong-joo! Why do you keep killing people!
紅朱！妳為什麼總是殺人？
Why can't I kill them? They'll die anyway.
為什麼不能殺？反正他們都會死的
-You were a mountain god once! -Why are you so tough on me?
-妳可是當過山神的！ -對我這麼兇做什麼？
Yeon killed tons of soldiers, but why go easy on him?
阿硯殺了數不清的日本兵 妳為什麼不罰他？
That's because the Yeon in Myoyeongak is--
因為妙緣閣的那個阿硯是…
Hey!
喂！
Yeon is what?
阿硯是什麼？
What is it? What aren't you telling me?
怎麼了？有什麼事瞞著我嗎？
So much talk for someone who's to be punished for murder!
一個即將因為殺人受罰的罪人 哪來的那麼多廢話！
Send her to Ice Hell.
送她去寒冰地獄
Hong-joo is getting old too. Why not send her somewhere warm?
紅朱年齡也大了 不如換個暖和的地方吧？
Let's go.
走吧
Oh, that's right.
對了
-You know Moo-yeong is here, right? -What?
-妳知道無影來了吧？ -什麼？
What do you mean? Moo-yeong is alive?
什麼意思？無影還活著？
-You weren't the one who saved him? -Hong-joo.
-不是妳救他的嗎？ -紅朱
Why do you think I turned him, who I treated like my own, into stone?
妳猜我為什麼 把親如兒子的無影變成石柱？
He is the one who annihilated everything from the mountain he ruled
是他親手毀掉了 他曾經掌管的那座山上
with his own hands.
所有的生命
There's no way.
不可能
Why would he do something like that?
他怎麼會那樣做？
Do you think I would've forgiven him, after all he's done?
他犯下了滔天罪行 妳覺得我還會原諒他嗎？
No.
不會
You would never.
永遠不會
Take her away.
帶她走吧
Who in the world saved him?
究竟是誰救他的？
And for what?
又是出於什麼目的？
Rang.
阿朗
Shin-ju!
申炷！
Anyone there?
有人嗎？
Rang's pocket watch.
阿朗的懷錶
And Shin-ju's handkerchief.
申炷的手帕
Damn it.
該死
For goodness' sake!
我的天！
Is anyone there?
有人嗎？
Anybody is welcome, so just help me.
誰都可以，幫我一下
Please, please!
拜託啦！
Please.
拜託
Who are you?
是誰？
A kid?
一個小孩？
Can you read this letter for me?
可以幫我看看這封信嗎？
"Your brother and Shin-ju are dying.
“你的弟弟和申炷都命懸一線
If you wish to save them,
如果想救他們
come to the hermitage at the east foot of Mt. Bukhan.
來北韓山東麓的寺院找我
I'll give you an hour.
我等你一個小時
You know who I am, don't you?"
你知道我是誰吧？”
Red-white mask, you bastard.
該死的紅白面具人
Hey, kid. Please help me out.
小孩，幫幫我吧
-Carry me. -Sure.
-背我 -好
-This way. -This way?
-這邊 -這邊嗎？
Help!
救命！
Please save us!
請救救我們！
Is anyone there?
有人嗎？
If they wanted to save us, would they have put us in here?
如果他們想救我們 還會把我們扔在這裡嗎？
We're about to die. I must try whatever I can, no?
我們快死了，我總要想想辦法吧？
Untie the rope first.
先解開繩索
I can't do it by force.
我再用力也掙脫不了
-Lord Lee Yeon will come to save us. -The guy who can't even see? You wish.
-李硯大人會來救我們的 -那個瞎子嗎？做夢吧
Even if he loses all his hands and feet, Lord Lee Yeon will come to save you.
即便李硯大人失去手腳 他也會來救你的
And you will do the same for him.
你對他也一樣
How would you know that?
你怎麼知道？
Stop talking like you know me.
不要假裝了解我了
I can't explain it, but I just know. I know how kind you are.
我不能解釋，但我就是知道 我知道你有多善良
You even bought me a kimchi fridge!
你甚至買了一個泡菜冰箱送給我！
Who the hell are you guys? Is that also a secret?
你們究竟是什麼人？這也是祕密嗎？
After living like strangers for hundreds of years, suddenly--
幾百年來形同陌路，突然間…
Cut it out. It's disgusting.
少來啦，很噁心
I think the water level is rising!
水位好像在上升！
Lord Lee Yeon!
李硯大人！
Thank you, kid.
謝謝妳，小孩
The sound of a moktak.
木魚的聲音
This way.
這邊
It's the stride of an adult man.
是成年男子的腳步聲
It's not human. It's him!
不是人類，是他！
Damn it.
該死
He's missing on purpose.
他是故意射偏的
He's messing with me, like we're playing hare and hounds.
他在耍我，這就像一場狩獵遊戲
Shit.
該死
If only I could see…
如果能看到…
If only I could see!
如果能看到該多好！
You know me, don't you?
你認識我對不對？
How do you know me?
你怎麼會認識我呢？
Why the hell are you doing this to me?
你究竟為什麼要這樣對我？
Take it.
拿去
I don't know what it is, but it's all my fault.
我不知道其中緣由 但這一切都是我的錯
I have no intention of fighting you. So, please…
我沒打算和你打架，所以拜託你…
Just spare Rang and Shin-ju, please.
放過阿朗和申炷吧，拜託啦
That's a lightning rod for you.
那是你的聚雷針
Damn it. Geez.
該死，真是的
Just a little more!
再用一點力！
We got it! We got it!
成功了！
What?
什麼？
What's that rope?
那根繩子是怎麼回事？
No. No, no!
不行！
At this rate, we'll both die.
照這樣下去，我們兩個都會死的
What do we do?
怎麼辦？
Lord Lee Rang!
李朗大人！
Rang!
阿朗！
Shin-ju!
申炷！
Please return my eyes.
請把眼睛還給我
Please give me back my sight. Please!
請把視力還給我，拜託了！
Guess who.
猜猜我是誰
This voice. Are you the kid from earlier?
這個聲音，妳是之前那個小孩嗎？
-No way. Are you-- -Saetani.
-不可能，妳是… -塞陀尼
It was you. You took my eyes!
是妳，是妳奪走了我的眼睛！
-Give them back! -You broke your promise first!
-還給我！ -是你先違背諾言的！
Guess my name.
猜猜我的名字
Your name? How the hell would I know?
妳的名字？我怎麼會知道？
-Die! -Where are you?
-去死吧！ -妳在哪裡？
There you are.
找到妳了
The sound of bells.
鈴鐺的聲音
This sound…
這個聲音…
This is the forest I used to rule.
這是我曾經掌管的森林
The carp you just saved is a descendant of the owner of this pond.
妳剛救的那條鯉魚 是這個池塘的主人的後代
I'll give you this as a reward.
我把這個送給妳，作為獎勵
What's this?
這是什麼？
I'll grant you a wish, just once.
我可以滿足妳一個願望，就一個
What's your name?
妳叫什麼名字？
My name is…
我的名字是…
I am…
我叫…
Tell me.
告訴我
Say it. What is your name?
說啊，妳叫什麼名字？
Tell me. Tell me right now!
告訴我，快告訴我！
Say it!
說啊！
I'm hungry.
我餓了
-We're almost home. Hang in there. -Okay.
-我們就快到家了，忍一下 -好
I'll go with this child.
我選這個小孩
I don't want to go, Sis.
姊姊，我不想走
I'm scared.
我害怕
Let's swap our clothes.
我們交換衣服吧
Don't go.
不要走
Sis…
姊姊…
I want to go home.
我想回家
I'm thirsty.
我好渴
I don't want to die.
我不想死
Please save me, mountain god.
山神，請救救我
I shouldn't have swapped clothes with her.
我不該和妹妹交換衣服的
I hate you all.
我恨你們所有人
My father, my sister, and the gods.
我的父親、我的妹妹，還有山神
I want to go home.
我想回家
I don't want to die.
我不想死
Mountain god.
山神
Help me. Please help me.
救救我，拜託了
Please save me. Save me, please.
拜託你救救我
Please, sir, mountain god. Please.
拜託了，山神大人，救救我
Please save me.
請你救救我
Help me. Please help me…
救救我，拜託了
Why didn't you come?
你為什麼沒有來？
By then, I was no longer…
那時候，我已經…
a mountain god.
不是山神了
I abandoned my duty to save a woman.
為了救一個女人 我拋棄了我的職責
Now you can't save anyone!
現在你救不了任何人！
I'm sorry…
對不起…
for being too late.
我來晚了
I'm so sorry.
真的對不起
My name is…
我的名字是…
I remembered your name.
我記起妳的名字了
My name?
我的名字？
Your name…
妳的名字是…
"Lea," as in Azalea flowers.
“鵑子”，杜鵑花的“鵑”
…is Lea.
…鵑子
As in Azaleas.
杜鵑花的“鵑”
My name…
我的名字是…
is Lea.
鵑子
Nothing can lock you up now.
現在沒有什麼可以困住妳了
You don't have to live as a Saetani.
妳不必再當塞陀尼了
I'm not Saetani.
我不是塞陀尼
I am Lea.
我是鵑子
Yes, you're Lea.
對，妳是鵑子
You were scared, weren't you? Dying in there, all alone.
當時的妳很害怕吧？ 一個人在那裡奄奄一息
In your next life,
下一世
be born as a normal child.
當一個普通小孩吧
Whether a shaman or a Saetani,
無論是巫師還是塞陀尼
let's not live as someone else's object.
都不要成為別人的物品
You did well.
辛苦妳了
Enduring in this small body.
用小小的身體熬過這一切
Thanks for making my wish come true.
謝謝你實現我的願望
Your brother is in the west well.
你弟弟在西井裡
Shin-ju.
申炷
You're almost up.
就快上來了
Are you okay? What about Rang?
沒事吧？阿朗呢？
He still in there.
他還在裡面
ICE HELL
（寒冰地獄）
So the old hag didn't save Moo-yeong.
原來老妖婆沒有救無影
But Moo-yeong and Yeon showed up in Gyeongseong on the same day…
但是無影和阿硯同一天出現在京城
You two…
你們兩個…
What the hell are you?
究竟是什麼東西？
Rang, can you recognize me?
阿朗，認得出我嗎？
Oh, what a relief.
太好啦
It's still fun messing with Yeon.
耍弄阿硯依然很好玩
Yeon.
阿硯
You'll be stuck in the past forever…
你將被永遠地困在過去
seeing everything you cared for die before your eyes.
看著你在乎的一切在眼前死去
That day, I made my first bucket list.
那一天，我做了第一份遺願清單
Can you move your legs?
你可以動動腿嗎？
Even if I were to leave, I'd wish Rang had someone by his side.
即便我要走 我依然希望阿朗身邊有人陪伴
And at the very least,
至少
I won't allow something like the red-white mask live
我不允許紅白面具人那樣的混蛋
in an era they're living in.
活在他們生活的時代
Red-white mask, who is it?
紅白面具人是誰？
-He knows me, no? -Shush.
-他認識我對不對？ -噓
You guys have already drawn me into your dog fight.
你們已經把我捲入了你們的混戰
The item revives the dead,
用這個物品
when you measure the length and width of a corpse.
測量屍體的長度和寬度 便可以使人起死回生
-Baby. -Let's knock it out.
-寶寶 -打暈好了
Hey, it's damp.
濕濕的
-Is this human? -Get him!
-這是人類嗎？ -抓住他！
Isn't it a demon in disguise?
不是偽裝成人類的妖怪嗎？
-What's your ideal type? -Someone stronger than me.
-你的理想型是什麼樣子？ -比我強大的人
Why did you come to this era?
你來這個時代做什麼？
You think I'm fake?
你以為我是假的？
I may have to kill one of them with my own hands.
我可能不得不親手殺死他們其中一位
Please, don't go.
拜託妳不要走
TRANSLATED BY TIFFANY NAYEON HWANG
字幕翻譯：鄒琳